-*- 学生们知道 -*-
It's not frivolous to ask teachers to engage
要求教师进行自我认识的旅程
in a journey of self knowledge.
并不是轻率的。
It's not frosting on the cake to ask them to explore
要求他们探索谁在教书、
who is it that's teaching, who are you the teacher.
作为老师的你是谁，也并不是锦上添花之事。
It's absolutely core and critical
如果我们想让教师成长，
if we want to grow teachers and the practice of teaching
想让教学实践以及年轻人的学习成果得到提高，
and the outcomes of learning for young people.
这些探索绝对是核心和关键。
Just think for a moment about the situations
请想一想，我们每个人
in which any one of us has learned the most.
在哪些情况下学到的东西最多。
I would bet a lot of money
我敢打赌，
that that learning has not come from
这种学习不是来自于
teachers who hid behind the podium,
那些躲在讲台后面、
hid behind a mask, hid behind the power of the grade,
躲在面具后面、躲在年级权力后面
hid behind their role of authority.
以及躲在他们权威角色后面的教师。
I'll bet a lot of money that
我敢打赌，
most learning in most people's lives
大多数人生活中的大部分学习
comes from teachers who engaged them on some level.
在某种程度上都来自于与他们接触的老师。
Now the forms of engagement are many and
在教学中，让学生参与的形式有很多，
varied and wondrously diverse.
而且多种多样，可谓应有尽有。
Some teachers are very shy
有些老师非常害羞，
and they don't know how to engage you eyeball to eyeball
他们不知道如何与学生进行眼神的交流，
but they have a passion that engages you with the subject.
但他们有一种让学生参与到该学科学习中的热情。
They're trying to share the richness of their
他们试图着与学生分享
of the life of their mind with their students.
自己丰富的心灵生活。
Other teachers have a much more user
其他老师有一种
friendly way of going about it
更用户友好的方式，
but one thing I can guarantee you is that
但有一件事我可以向你保证，
students know when a teacher is being real.
学生们都知道什么时候老师是真实的。
And they get involved with that teacher
他们与那个老师打交道，
and students know when a teacher is phoning it in
而当学生知道老师在夸夸其谈时，
and students turn off.
学生们就会避而不听了。
My favorite story about teaching is about
我最喜欢的教学故事是
a young woman who was asked to tell about
关于一个年轻女人，她被要求讲述她
a good or great teacher that she had had.
过往的一个优秀的或伟大的老师的故事。
And she said well I've had a bunch of them
她说，我有很多老师，
but I can't possibly tell you about them
但我不可能告诉你他们的故事，
because they are all so different from one another.
因为他们都是如此不同。
But she said I can tell you about my bad teachers
但她说，我可以告诉你那些差劲老师，
because they're all the same.
因为他们都是一样的。
And the interviewer said, oh, what do you mean?
采访者说，哦，你是什么意思？
And she said,
她说，
with my bad teachers, their words,
那些差劲老师，他们讲话时，
float somewhere in front of their faces
就像卡通片中人物讲话一样，
like the balloon speech in cartoons.
其话语在他们脸前的某个地方漂浮着。
And when I heard that I thought,
当我听到这句话时，我想，
what a remarkable image of bad teaching.
这是一个多么糟糕的差劲老师的形象。
It's an image of the stuff being taught
这是一种被教导的东西与
separated from the self who's teaching it
教它的人在真实性上
in authenticity, unreal.
不一致相分离的形象。
And students know when there is that gap
学生们知道，当教师的自我身份和
between the selfhood of the teacher
他们在房间里做的任何事情
and whatever it is they're doing in the room
之间存在落差时，
and because the students are disconnected
因为学生们被切断了联系，
since the teacher himself or herself is disconnected,
因为教师自己也被切断了联系，
no learning can happen.
所以不可能发生学习。
Learning is about making connections at
学习是为了建立联系，
more than connections,
而不仅仅是连接，
it's about jumping sparks between the poles.
它是在两极之间共舞的火花。
And it doesn't happen when a teacher is unplugged.
而当老师从中失联时，是不可能发生学习的。